Prakash Agrahari



sshivamprakashh301@gmail.com



8559075258



linkedin.com/in/prakash-agrahari-a5655312b



https://prakash-agrahari.vercel.app/

Summary

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in HTML, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), JSON, Github, and Bootstrap. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor's degree focused in Electrical, Electronics and Communications Engineering from Lovely Professional University.

Experience



Frontend Developer

Torinit Technologies Inc.

Jun 2022 - Present

Worked in the complex portal web app called Senara Triangle, having a portal for Admin, Super-Admin, and users.

- Worked with Canadian clients, and developed and troubleshooted the problems clients had.
 Worked on projects having state-management tools like redux saga.
- Developed 30+ user-facing features via React JS.
- Developed the structures & layouts as per user requirements with

100% clients satisfaction

- Troubleshoot and debug the Applications code for smooth exceptions and improved stability.
- Technologies Used: React JS, Jira, Git, Redux.

ASKFast Frontend Developer

ASK-Fast

Dec 2021 - May 2022

Worked in the complex portal web app called SOL, having a portal for Admin, therapist, psychotherapist & supervising – therapist.

- Developed protected route components for Authentication.
- Worked with international clients, and developed and troubleshot the problems clients had.
 Worked on projects having state-management tools like redux-saga.
- Technologies Used: React JS, Jira, Git, Redux.



🧘 Frontend Developer

Riser Techub

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021

Worked with various gaming web applications with complex UI as well logic contained.

- Configured Redux data flow between React components for logical separation of client-side logic and API calls.
- Worked and developed games like Roulette using React Js.
- Implemented Lazy loading into the application that reduced the initial loading time and made it 40% faster on the browser.

- made utilities of the reused functions and imported were needed to make the code cleaner.
- Technologies Used: React JS, Jira, Git, Redux.

Software Engineer

Rayabhari Technologies Pvt. Ltd

Jan 2021 - Aug 2021

Project Desc. Dentamitra is an oral health tracking app

with artificial intelligence which has a

scanner to detect cavities and other

issues. And also it has the admin panel

which is a web app where dentists can

schedule the meetings booked by the user

from the dentamitra app. I got an

opportunity to work with a web app and

the native app both of dentamitra.

Technology React JS, Ionic React.

Responsibilities

Integrated new features like

Payment, Zoom Call, Whatsapp, and Call in a mobile app!

• Bug fix in Appointment Booking

Functionalities

Education



High School, Science

2009 - 2011

Jwala Devi Saraswati Vidya Mandir

Intermediate, Science

2011 - 2013

Lovely Professional University

Bachelor's degree, Electrical, Electronics and Communications Engineering 2014 - 2018

Licenses & Certifications

Problem Solving (basic) - HackerRank

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/c70d831c5de1

Problem Solving (Intermediate) - HackerRank

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/a48f081ffe88

(A) JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures - freeCodeCamp

https://www.freecodecamp.org/certification/prakash.agrahari/javascript-algorithms-and-data-structures

Modern JavaScript for React JS - ES6. - Udemy

https://udemy-certificate.s3.amazonaws.com/pdf/UC-d6463958-8fa3-4e73-85dd-fc2442686c65.pdf

Cutshort Certified React.js - Basic - Cutshort

https://cutshort.io/certificate/58172

Skills

JavaScript • React.js • Semantic UI • HTML5 • GitHub • HTML • Material-UI • Ant Design • Redux.js • TypeScript